Guide to the Lydia Winston Malbin Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1959-1989; Series VI; (5.5 boxes)
  - H (Box 42, Folder 616)
  - I (Box 42, Folder 617)
  - Jackson, Martha (Box 42, Folder 618)
  - Juries, 1962-1963 (Box 42, Folder 619)
  - K (Box 42, Folder 620)
  - Kuh, Katherine (Box 43, Folder 621)
  - Kahn, Albert [brother] and Ernestine (Mrs.Albert) [mother], 1950-1951, undated (Box 43, Folder 622)
  - L (Box 43, Folder 623)
  - M (Box 43, Folder 624)
  - Marinetti, Benedetta (Box 43, Folder 625)
  - Marlborough-Gerson Gallery (Box 43, Folder 626)
  - Martin, Marianne (Box 43, Folder 627)
  - N-O (Box 43, Folder 628)
  - P (Box 43, Folder 629)
  - R (Box 43, Folder 630)
  - Rich, Daniel (Box 43, Folder 631)
  - S (Box 43, Folder 632)
  - Sandberg, Willem (Box 44, Folder 633)
  - Severini, Gino (Box 44, Folder 634)
  - Solley, Thomas T., 1978 (Box 44, Folder 635)
  - Spivak, Peter, 1975-1984 (Box 44, Folder 636-637)
  - Stieglitz, Alfred;To & about (Box 44, Folder 638)
  - Sweeney, James (Box 44, Folder 639)
  - T (Box 45, Folder 640)
  - Taylor, Joshua (Box 45, Folder 641)
  - V (Box 45, Folder 642)
  - Valentiner, Wilhelm Reinhold (Box 45, Folder 643)
  - Vogel, Edna [Textiles in Winston House, Birmingham, Michigan] (Box 45, Folder 644)
  - Von Wiegand, Charmion (Box 45, Folder 645)
  - W (Box 45, Folder 646)
  - Winston, Harry L. (Box 45, Folder 647)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 45, Folder 648)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 649)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 650)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 651)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 652)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 653)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1978 (Box 45, Folder 654)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 655)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 656)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 657)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 658)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 659)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 660)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 661)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1970 (Box 46, Folder 662)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1969 (Box 46, Folder 663)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 664)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 665)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 666)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 667)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 668)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1963 (Box 46, Folder 669)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1962 (Box 46, Folder 670)
- Personal Photographs, 1949-1972; Series VII; (1.5 boxes)
  This series consists of personal photographs of Lydia Winston Malbin, her family, her friends, and her residences. Each photograph has a number assigned to it, as indicated by a small label on the back.
  Photographs are arranged in the order in which Mrs. Malbin seems to have kept them.
  - Lydia Winston Malbin in library (Box 47, Folder 671)
  - Lydia Winston Malbin with Collection, 1950s-1972 (Box 47, Folder 672-675)
  - Lydia Winston Malbin receiving honorary degree, Wayne State University, 1961 (Box 47, Folder 676)
  - Lydia Winston Malbin with Harry L. Winston, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 677-678)
  - Lydia Winston Malbin with Dr. Barnett Malbin (Box 47, Folder 679)
  - House in Birmingham, Michigan, Downstairs (Box 47, Folder 680-690)
  - Calder Mobile Photographs, 1954-1960s (Box 47, Folder 691)
  - Art World Photographs, Friends and Artists, 1954-1962 (Box 47, Folder 692-712)
  - Photographs of Lydia Winston Malbin's apartment, taken by her granddaughter, Lydia Robinson (Box 48, Folder 713-718)
  - Photographs of model of Malbin exhibit (Box 48, Folder 719)
  - Photographs of Boccioni, his family and friends (Box 48, Folder 720-722)
- Gifts and Loans, 1945-1985; Series VIII; (8.5 boxes)
  This series consists of the documentation for each work of art donated or lent by Malbin.
  The files within this series are primarily arranged alphabetically according to artist, with some files arranged according to gifts to individuals and institutions. Within each folder, the material is arranged as Malbin kept it.
  - Gifts
    - Itemized Lists, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 723)
    - To Ernestine W. Ruben, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 724)
    - To Sally & Eliot Robinson, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 725)
    - To Sally Robinson (Box 48, Folder 726)
    - To Harry Winston, Jr., 1976 (Box 48, Folder 727)
  - To Institutions
    - Tax Authority - Information Required for Gifts, 1966-1967 (Box 48, Folder 728)
    - Albion College (Box 48, Folder 729)
    - Art Institute of Chicago, 1954-1957 (Box 48, Folder 730)
    - Cranbrook - Auction, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 731)
    - Detroit Institute of Art (Box 48, Folder 732)
    - Detroit Institute of Art - graphics (Box 48, Folder 733)
    - Detroit Institute of Art - Miss Ellen Sharp (Box 48, Folder 734)
    - Donations (Box 48, Folder 735)
    - To Individuals/Institutions (Box 48, Folder 736)
  - Individual Works
    - Adams, Robert
      - "Maquette for Architectural Screen -- Square Snake", (sculpture) 1956 (#150);Gift to: Harry Winston, Jr. 1962 (Box 49, Folder 737)
    - Agam, Jacob
      - Miscellaneous (Box 49, Folder 738)
    - Alechinsky, Pierre
      - "Composition", (painting) 1960;Gift to: DIA, 1966 (Box 49, Folder 739)
      - "Le Part du Visible" (#193) (Box 49, Folder 740-741)
    - Anthoons, Willy
      - "Monde Interieur", (carved wood sculpture) 1949 (#159);Gift to: DIA, 1959, 1960 (Box 49, Folder 742)
    - Appel, Karel
      - "Head and Fish", (painting) 1954 (#142) 1955;Gift to: DIA, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 743-744)
    - Arnal, Francois
      - "The Gallery" (painting) 1954 (#143);Gift to Harry Winston, Jr., n.d. (Box 49, Folder 745)
    - Bacci, Edmondo
      - "Avvenimento", (painting) 1956;Gift to: Harry Winston, Jr., n.d., circa 1956 (Box 49, Folder 746)
    - Baj, Enrico
      - "Erano Tutti e 3 Buona Strada" (painting) 1961;Gift to: Harry Winston, Jr. 1967 (Box 49, Folder 747)
      - "The Grand Uniform", (painting) c.1961 (#130);Gift to: Ernestine Ruben (Box 50, Folder 748)
    - Benner, Gerrit
      - "Composition", (painting) 1961 (#197) 1963;Gift to: Ernestine Ruben, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 749)
    - Bourke-White, Margaret
      - "Bolshevik Babies in the Nursery, Amo Automobile Factory, Moscow, 1934" (photograph);Gift to: DIA, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 750)
    - Braques, George
      - "Fox", (etching) 1911 (#G-158);Gift to: DIA, 1970, 1954 (Box 50, Folder 751)
      - "Mermaid and Dolphin", (etching) (#G-11);Gift to: DIA, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 752)
    - Broner, Robert
      - "Paths of Power", (intaglio) 1967 (#G-516);Gift to: Douglas Mann (Box 50, Folder 753)
    - Calder, Alexander
      - "Flying Saucers", (lithograph) 1968 (#G-570);Gift to: MOMA, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 754)
      - Foundation Maeght Poster, (lithograph) 1969 (#G-583);Gift to: ? (Box 50, Folder 755)
    - Campigli, Massimo
      - "Les Amis" 1951;Purchased to be gift to: Sally Robinson, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 756)
    - Capognossi, Giuseppe
      - "Superficie #86", 1954;Gift to: Ernestine Ruben, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 757)
    - Chadwick, Lynn
      - "Rock", (sculpture), 1955;Gift to: Harry Winston, Jr. (Box 50, Folder 758)
    - Condopoulos, Alekos
      - "Ombre di Notte", (painting) 1959/60 1960;Loaned to: Sally and Eliot Robinson (Box 50, Folder 759)
    - Consagra, Pietro
      - "Abstract Composition", (painting) (#56) 1958;Gift to: Ernestine Ruben (Box 50, Folder 760)
        The Yale Art Gallery Finding Aid lists Courbet, Gustave, "Landscape with Torrent";Gift to: DIA, 1972;(from Albert Kahn Collection) as being within this folder. Currently not found.
    - Couzijn, Wessel
      - "Icarus", (sculpture), n.d. (#178);Loaned to: Sally Robinson, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 761-762)
      - "Composition No. IV", (lithograph) 1963 (#G-310);Gift to: Eliot Robinson (Box 51, Folder 763)
    - Davie, Alan
      - "Hat Trick", (painting) 1960;Gift to: Sally Robinson, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 764)
      - "Trick for the King", (painting) 1960;Gift to: Sally Robinson, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 765)
    - Deluigi, Mario
      - "Study of Voids", (painting) 1953-54 (#155);Gift to: Ernestine Ruben, 1954 (Box 51, Folder 766)
    - DiGiorgio, Giorgio
      - "La Colombe du Cop" (sculpture) (#157);Gift to: Ernestine Ruben (Box 51, Folder 767)
    - Dorazio, Piero
      - "Composition", Documenta III, (lithograph, color) 1964 (#G-550) (Box 51, Folder 768)
    - Dubuffet, Jean
      - "Gravelle", (lithograph) (#G-208);Gift to: DIA, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 769)
      - "Puppet Master" (collage), 1954;Gift to: Sally and Eliot Robinson (Box 51, Folder 770)
    - Dumitresco, Natalia
      - "Composition", (drawing, ink) n.d. (#G-180) n.d.;no information, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 771)
    - Ernst, Jimmy
      - "Cirque d'Hiver II", (painting) 1952 ;Gift to: Cranbrook Academy of Art, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 772)
    - Franchina, Nino
      - "Abstraction" (sculpture);Gift to: Barbara Winston, 1968, 1959 (Box 51, Folder 773)
    - Giacometti, Alberto
      - "The Couple", (sculpture) 1926;Gift to: Art Institute of Chicago, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 774)
      - "The Couple": legal documents (Box 52, Folder 775)
      - Internal Revenue Service Audit (Box 52, Folder 776)
      - "Fête de Chat", (lithograph) 1954;Gift to: DIA, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 777)
    - Hartley, Marsden
      - "Rope and Sea Shells", (painting) 1940;Gift to: Harry Winston, Jr., 1948 (Box 52, Folder 778)
    - Hartung, Hans
      - "L6" (lithograph, color) 1966 (#G-659) 1971;Gift to: Sally Robinson (Box 52, Folder 779)
    - Heckel, Erich
      - "Belgian Landscape" (lithograph) (#G-255);Gift to: DIA, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 780)
    - Hennessey, Timothy
      - (Watercolor) 1960;Gift to: Sally & Eliot Robinson (Box 52, Folder 781)
    - Heyboer, Anton
      - (Etching, color);Gift to: ? (Box 52, Folder 782)
    - Honegger-Levater, G.
      - (Painting), n.d.;Gift to: Harry L. Winston, Jr., 1954 (Box 52, Folder 783)
    - Jansson, Louise
      - (Watercolor) 1954;Gift to: Sally Robinson (Box 52, Folder 784)
    - Jongkind, Johan Barthold
      - (Watercolor), n.d.;Gift to: American Federation of Arts, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 785)
    - Jorn, Asger
      - Lithograph from: "Jubilaeum-serien" (lithograph, color), 1963 (Box 52, Folder 786)
      - "Suicide of Mr. H." (painting), 1961;Gift to: DIA, 1978, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 787)
    - Kandinsky, Wassily
      - "Klein Welten VII" (wood-cut), 1922 (#G-51);Gift to: DIA, 1967 (Box 52, Folder 788)
    - Klee, Paul
      - "2 Trees" (gouache);Gift to: University of Michigan?, 1956? (Box 52, Folder 789)
    - Knaths, Karl
      - "Head" (painting), 1945;[NOTE: first purchase from Rose Fried] (Box 52, Folder 790)
    - Koutroulis, Aris
      - (Pastel drawing) (#237);Gift to: Sally Robinson, 1974, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 791)
    - Krajcberg, Frans
      - "Composition" (gouache), 1959;Gift to: ?, 1960 (Box 52, Folder 792)
      - "Estampage" No.1 (woodcut) (#G-381) 1964;Gift to: Ernestine Ruben (Box 52, Folder 793)
    - Kuniyoshi, Yasuo
      - "Head of a Young Girl" (painting), 1937;Gift to: ? (Box 52, Folder 794)
    - Lachaise, Gaston
      - "Woman, Arms Akimbo" (sculpture) 1910-12 (Box 53, Folder 795)
    - Latapie, Louis
      - "Cariatide Du Reve" (painting), 1953 (#163);Gift to Ernestine Ruben, 1954 (Box 53, Folder 796)
    - Lataster, Ger
      - "Composition" (etching), 1961;Gift to: Harry L. Winston, Jr. (Box 53, Folder 797)
    - Laurens, Henri
      - "Nu Accroupi" (lithograph), 1951 (#G-75 [G-13?]);Gift to: Ernestine Ruben, undated (Box 53, Folder 798)
    - Leger, Ferdinand
      - "Landscape" (Box 53, Folder 799)
    - Levine, Les
      - "Windows" (3 collages);Gift to: Erica Ruben, 1988, 1969 (Box 53, Folder 800)
    - Levison, Mon
      - "Overlapping Squares in Flux" (painting), 1967 (#45) (Box 53, Folder 801)
    - Lucebert (L. G. Swanswijk)
      - "Hungry Children" (painting), 1969 (#177);Gift to: Sally & Eliot Robinson, circa 1962 (Box 53, Folder 802)
      - "Klein Circus" (etching) (#G-211);Gift to Peter & Corinne Robinson, 1962 (Box 53, Folder 803)
    - Luderowski, Theodore
      - "Composition in Space";Gift to: Sally Robinson, 1954 (Box 53, Folder 804)
    - Maillol, Aristide
      - "Daphnis Playing on his Pipe", 1926;Gift to: Barbara Kahn, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 805)
    - Marini, Marino
      - (Two gouaches);Gift to: DIA, 1951 (Box 53)
    - Metzinger, Jean
      - "Still Life with Lamp" (painting), 1916;Gift to: MOMA, 1960, 1953 (Box 53, Folder 806)
    - Mignot, Ma
      - "No. X" (drawing, ink) (#G-579);Gift to: ?;"No. XIII" (drawing, ink), 1969 (Box 53, Folder 807)
    - Mirko, Basaldella
      - "Woman Drinking at a River" (sculpture), c. 1954 (#29);Gift to: Sally Robinson (Box 53, Folder 808)
    - Miro, Joan
      - Portfolio of 13 Lithographs (Box 53, Folder 809)
      - "V-1944" of Barcelona Series (lithograph: 5/5) (#G-56) (Box 53, Folder 810)
    - Mitchell, Wallace
      - Untitled (painting), n.d.;Gift to: Harry Winston, Jr., undated (Box 53, Folder 811)
      - "Variations Without Theme" (painting), 1946 n.d.;Gift to: Harry Winston (Box 53, Folder 812)
    - Modigliani, Amadeo
      - "Greek Head" (crayon drawing), n.d. 1947;Gift to: Sally Robinson (Box 53, Folder 813)
    - Mortenson-Vasarely
      - Portfolio;Gift to: Kalamazoo Art Center, 1968 (Box 53, Folder 814)
    - Moser, Wilfred
      - "Ancient Mariner and the Albatross", 1960;Gift to: Sally Robinson (Box 53, Folder 815)
    - Nesch, Rolf
      - "The Blue Mask" (intaglio, color), (#G-581);Gift to: DIA? (Box 53, Folder 816)
      - "Gengis Kahn" (intaglio, color), (#G-273) 1949;Gift to: DIA, 1969, 1962 (Box 53, Folder 817)
    - Newton, Gordon
      - (Drawing) (#G-670);Gift to: Sally Robinson, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 818)
    - Packard, David
      - "Stranger with Eyes" (sculpture), 1961-61 (#190);Gift to: Harry Winston, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 819)
    - Paolozzi, Edouardo
      - "Head" (sculpture), 1957 (#44);Gift to: University of Michigan Museum, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 820)
      - "Head", RE: Gift to: University of Michigan (Box 54, Folder 821)
    - Perlmuter, Pearl
      - "Mouvement" (etching) (#G-183);Gift to: Jane Hickey, Aug 1971 (Box 54, Folder 822)
    - Picasso, Pablo
      - "Picasso Exposition Vallauris" (affiche, woodcut) (#G-24); "Potteries de Picasso" (affiche, lithograph) (#G-43) (Box 54, Folder 823)
      - "Vallauris 1952 Exposition" (lithograph, color) (#G-240) (Box 54, Folder 824)
    - Rauschenberg, Robert
      - "Rival" (lithograph), 1963 (#G-370) 1964;Gift to:DIA, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 825)
    - Richier, Germaine
      - "La Monte Religieuse" ("Praying Mantis") (sculpture) (#196) (Box 54, Folder 826)
    - Rosso, Mino
      - "Man in Motion" (sculpture);Gift to: University of Michigan 1959, 1958 (Box 54, Folder 827)
    - Roualt, Georges
      - "Small Family" (etching) (#G-160) 1948;Gift to: University of Michigan (Box 54, Folder 828)
    - Salvatore (Messina)
      - "Figura Marina" ("Sea Figure") (sculpture), 1952;Gift to: DIA (Box 54, Folder 829)
    - Santomaso, Giuseppe
      - "Composition" (painting), 1956 (#175);Gift to: Harry Winston, Jr (Box 55, Folder 830)
    - Scaldini, Giuditta
      - "Figurine" (sculpture), 1951 (#64);Gift to: Harry Winston, Jr. (Box 55, Folder 831)
    - Schwartz, Leonard
      - "The Good Shepherd" (sculpture of rubble) 1951 (Box 55, Folder 832)
    - Seuphor, Michel
      - "Collage" (painting);Gift to: Harry & Joan Winston, 1959 (Box 55, Folder 833)
    - Signori, Carlo
      - "Autoritratto" ("White Portrait") (sculpture), 1958 (#153) (Box 55, Folder 834)
    - Skoglund, Sandy
      - Untitled II (drawing), 1977 (#261);Gift to: Lydia Robinson, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 835)
    - Sironi, Mario
      - "Composition" (gouache), 1918;Gift to: DIA, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 836)
    - Smith, Kimber
      - "Red China" [1965?];Gift to: Sally Robinson (Box 55, Folder 837)
    - Seaman, Francesco
      - "Ferito" 1st work, 1960 (#154), 1961 (Box 55, Folder 838-839)
    - Soutine, Chiam
      - "Red Gladioli" (painting), c.1919 (#2) 1948 (Box 55, Folder 840)
    - Stroud, Peter
      - "Green Circumvent with Blue" (painting), 1964 (#244);Gift to: Sally Robinson (Box 55, Folder 841)
    - Tancredi
      - "Swirling Composition";Gift to: Mr. & Mrs. Harry Winston, Jr. 1958 (Box 55, Folder 842)
    - Tanguy, Yves
      - "Shadow Country" ("terre d'ombre") (painting), 1927 (#73), 1951 (Box 56, Folder 843-844)
    - Todd, Mike
      - "Alba II" (sculpture), 1968 (#130);Gift to: Ernestine Ruben, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 845)
    - Vasarely, Victor de
      - "Utica" (painting), 1954-55;Gift to: Harry & Joan Winston, 1958 (Box 56, Folder 846)
    - Vincente, Esteban
      - Composition, 1958 (Box 56, Folder 847)
    - Other
      - Loans - Art Collection (Box 56, Folder 848)
      - Documents Sent Out (Box 56, Folder 849)
      - Photographs Sent Out, 1958-1985; 2 (Box 56, Folder 850-851)
      - Boccioni Catalog Raisonee: photographs sent out, 1982-1983 (Box 56, Folder 852)
- Collecting Art, 1951-1988; Series IX; (9 boxes)
  This series consists of material relating to Malbin's various collecting activities.
  Files are arranged in the order in which Malbin maintained them. While in some cases it is difficult to determine the reasoning for their placement, it was decided to maintain this order for two reasons: 1) numerous scholars have already utilized this material in this order; and 2) it may provide insight into Malbin's thought processes for a potential biographer.
  - Peabody Accession Book, Prior to 1961 (Box 57, Folder 853-857)
  - Early Acquisitions Diary, 1952 (Box 57, Folder 858)
  - Acquisitions Notebook, 1954-1956 (Box 57, Folder 859)
  - Notebook: "Winstons in Italy";(recorded by Harry L. Winston), 1960 (Box 57, Folder 860)
  - LWM: Noted re: Lacerba (Box 57, Folder 861)
  - Concerning the Acquisition of Early Italian Futurist Art by the Winstons, 1951-early 1960s, 1984 (Box 57, Folder 862)
  - Inventories (Box 57, Folder 863)
  - Inventories: Posters, 1971 (Box 57, Folder 864)
  - Affiche lists, 1966-1967 (Box 57, Folder 865)
  - "Cobra Works in the Lydia Winston Malbin Collection", 1987 (Box 57, Folder 866)
  - Joseph Klima: lists of photographs (Box 57, Folder 867)
  - Collection: Miscellaneous (including extra copies of some photographs) (Box 57, Folder 868)
  - Graphics exhibitions: bibliography, 1971 (Box 57, Folder 869)
  - Art Values (Box 57, Folder 870-871)
  - Requests for purchases from Winston Collection, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 872)
  - Restorers of paintings and sculpture:;Korany, Volkmer, et al., 1956, 1972, undated (Box 58, Folder 873)
  - Conservation: miscellaneous (Box 58, Folder 874)
  - Material from Milva H. Nagel, Paper Conservator for the Metropolitan Museum (Box 58, Folder 875)
  - Bills for books, 1945-1972, undated (Box 58, Folder 876)
  - Bills for shipment of paintings, 1958 (Box 58, Folder 877)
  - Bills for framing, 1959-1965 (Box 58, Folder 878)
  - Rubinger Gallery: bills for framing, 1967-1971 (Box 58, Folder 879)
  - John McKinney: bills for framing, 1968-1974, undated (Box 58, Folder 880)
  - Joseph Klima, photographer: bills, 1970-1973 (Box 58, Folder 881)
  - Klein/Vogel Gallery: invoices, 1971-1974 (Box 58, Folder 882)
  - Books in Winston Art Library, 1964, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 883)
  - Correspondence with Carlos Cardozzo (shipment of art), 1951-1963 (Box 58, Folder 884)
  - MOMA Futurism Exhibition Correspondence re: Canaday article, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 885)
  - Richardson, E.P. correspondence, etc., 1955-1959, undated (Box 58, Folder 886)
  - Visitors to Winston Collection: Peter Robinson's class, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 887)
  - Visitors, 1965-1972 (Box 58, Folder 888-889)
  - Visiting Groups, 1971-1988 (Box 59, Folder 890-891)
  - Student essays re: Futurism (Box 59, Folder 892)
  - Winston Collection: comments, 1967, 1972, 1981, undated (Box 59, Folder 893)
  - Dana Cramer (Box 59, Folder 894)
  - Futurist Documents
    - Copies of Futurist Documents collected by Morgan Russell (#1-30) (Box 59, Folder 895-896)
    - Russolo, Luigi;Document #1 (Box 59, Folder 897)
    - Futurist Manifesto (Box 59, Folder 898)
    - List of Futurist Documents (Box 59, Folder 899)
    - Correspondence re: Great Private Collections (with Nigel Nicolson, Douglas Cooper, Joshua Taylor), 1962-1963 (Box 60, Folder 900)
    - Correspondence with Art in America (including 'maps' of how works were displayed), 1968 (Box 60, Folder 901)
    - Correspondence: Arts Magazine, 1957-1958 (Box 60, Folder 902)
  - Exhibition Catalogs of the Winston Collection (Box 60, Folder 903-915)
  - Bibliography [of publications] containing works from the Winston, 1973 (Box 60, Folder 916)
  - TVS-WNET: Filming of Boccioni Unique Forms, 1988 (Box 60, Folder 917)
  - Publications re: futurism utilizing works from the Winston Collection, 1951-1967 (Box 61, Folder 918-919)
  - Publication re: Futurism, 1968-1977 (Box 61, Folder 920)
  - Publications-Correspondence re: works from the Winston Collection (Box 61, Folder 921)
  - Miscellaneous clippings: Winston/Malbin Collection (Box 61, Folder 922)
  - Articles re: futurist exhibitions (Box 61, Folder 923)
  - Miscellaneous art articles (Box 61, Folder 924-925)
  - Miscellaneous art articles: art collectors (Box 62, Folder 926A)
  - Miscellaneous articles re: Futurism (Box 62, Folder #926B)
  - Miscellaneous gallery publications re: Futurism (Box 62, Folder 927)
  - Miscellaneous material re: art collection (Box 62, Folder 928)
  - MOMA Futurist Exhibition: miscellaneous clippings, 1961 (Box 62, Folder 929)
  - Victor Miesel article re: Winston Collection, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 930)
  - Miscellaneous sources (Box 62, Folder 931)
  - Statements about modern art (Box 62, Folder 932)
  - Articles re: LWM, 1955-1967, 1974 (Box 62, Folder 933-936)
  - Articles re: LWM as art collector, 1957-1988 (Box 62, Folder 937)
  - Articles re: LWM - "Gallery", Friends of the Vassar Art Gallery, 1988 (Box 62, Folder 938)
  - Lecture on LWM by Ruth Rattner, 1987 (Box 62, Folder 939)
  - Secondary Materials
    - A (Box 63, Folder 940)
    - B (Box 63, Folder 941)
    - C (Box 63, Folder 942)
    - D (Box 63, Folder 943)
    - F (Box 63, Folder 944)
    - G-H (Box 63, Folder 945)
    - I-J (Box 63, Folder 946)
    - K-L (Box 63, Folder 947)
    - M (Box 63, Folder 948)
    - Monet, Claude (Box 63, Folder 949)
    - Moser, Wilfred (Box 63, Folder 950)
    - N-O (Box 63, Folder 951)
    - P (Box 63, Folder 952)
    - Picasso, Pablo (Box 64, Folder 953-955)
    - Pollock, Jackson (Box 64, Folder 956)
    - R (Box 64, Folder 957)
    - S-T (Box 64, Folder 958)
    - W (Box 64, Folder 959)
    - Abstract Art (Box 64, Folder 960)
    - Bauhaus (Box 64, Folder 961)
    - Constructivism (Box 64, Folder 962)
    - Cobra Group (Box 65, Folder 963)
    - Conceptual Art (Box 65, Folder 964)
    - Cubism (Box 65, Folder 965)
    - Dada (Box 65, Folder 966)
    - Futurism: correspondence and notes re: talk given by 'Virginia' (Box 65, Folder 967)
    - Non-Objective Art (Box 65, Folder 968)
    - Russian Avant-Garde (Box 65, Folder 969)
    - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 65, Folder 970)
    - Vorticism (Box 65, Folder 971)
    - Futurist poetry and books (Box 65, Folder 972)
    - Futurist bibliography (Box 65, Folder 973)
    - Pop Art (Box 65, Folder 974)
    - Post-Modernism (Box 65, Folder 975)
    - Surrealism (Box 65, Folder 976)
    - Tamarind Lithography Workshop (Box 65, Folder 977)
    - Futurist Music and Architecture (Box 65, Folder 978)
    - Futurism: Miscellaneous (Box 65, Folder 979)
    - Futurism: documentary film (Box 65, Folder 980)
    - Futurism (Box 65, Folder 981)
    - Dynamism of the Machine (Box 65, Folder 982)
    - LWM Manuscripts - College Art Association, 1966 (Box 65, Folder 983)